Back in time.
Men in Black 3 is a action, comedy, science fiction
film directed by Barry Sonnenfeld.
Agents J and K are back...in time.
J has seen some inexplicable things in his 15 years with the Men in Black, but nothing,
not even aliens, perplexes him as much as his wry, reticent partner.
But when K's life and the fate of the planet are put at stake, Agent J
will have to travel back in time to put things right.
J discovers that there are secrets to the universe that K never told him - secrets that will reveal themselves as
he teams up with the young Agent K to save his partner, the agency, and the future of humankind.
Agent J, played by Will Smith.
Agent K, played by Tommy Lee Jones.
Young Agent K, played by Josh Brolin.
Boris The Animal, played by Jemaine Clement.
Agent O, played by Emma Thompson.
Griffin, played by Michael Stuhlbarg.
Men in Black 3 (stylized as MIB³) is a 2012 American science fiction action
comedy film based on the Men in Black comic book series.
It is the third installment in the Men in Black film series.
Directed by Barry Sonnenfeld and written by Etan Cohen, the film stars Will Smith, Tommy Lee Jones and
Josh Brolin, with Jemaine Clement, Michael Stuhlbarg, and Emma Thompson in supporting roles.
In the film, Agent J is required to go back in time to prevent the assassination of his
partner Agent K, the fallout of which threatens the safety of Earth.
Development of the sequel began during filming of its predecessor,
with its premise suggested by Smith to Sonnenfeld.
Despite rumors of a fallout between Smith and Sonnenfeld during the filming of Men in
Black II, their returns were confirmed alongside Jones by May 2010.
David Koepp and Jeff Nathanson were later hired to perform uncredited rewrites to
Cohen's original screenplay and principal photography began that November.
Filming was split into two parts, first occurring between November and December 2010, and
restarting between April and June 2011, taking place primarily in New York City.
Composer Danny Elfman, who scored the previous two
installments, returned to score the third.
With a production budget of $215 million, it is one of
the most expensive films ever made.
Men in Black 3 premiered at O2 World in Berlin on May 14, 2012, and was
theatrically released in the United States on May 25.
It received generally positive reviews from critics, with praise for the performances of the cast
(particularly Brolin's), and was considered an improvement over its predecessor.
The film grossed $654.2 million worldwide, becoming the tenth-highest grossing film of 2012
and the highest grossing film in the franchise, unadjusted for inflation.
A standalone sequel, Men in Black: International, was released
in 2019, without most of the original cast.
The film explores themes of time travel, time
machine, based on comic, alien, buddy cop.
The tone is lighthearted and thought_provoking.